Guide to the Edwina Dumm Collection
The Ohio State University Billy Ireland Cartoon Library & Museum
Edwina Dumm Collection
1883-1987
The Ohio State University Billy Ireland Cartoon Library & Museum
Edwina, 1893-1990
13 boxes (and 2200 original cartoons)
Collection of original comic strips and cartoons, clippings of political cartoons, illustrated sheet music and miscellany.--Political cartoons and illustrations (1916-1917), Columbus Daily Monitor--Cap Stubbs and Tippie (daily comic strip) (1959-1961)--Tippie (Sunday strip) (1/18/48)--Alec the Great (dates unknown), with verses written by Robert Dennis Dumm--Sinbad (1923?)--sheet music: Shelter lullaby (1943); Tippie and the circus (1944); Tippie and the hurdy-gurdy (1947); Tippie's Hallowe'en serenade (1947); and the Christmas tree (1950)--photo, misc. papers, tape and transcript of oral history interview (2/15/85)
SPEC.CGA.FED
Biography of Edwina Dumm
Frances Edwina Dumm was born in Upper Sandusky, Ohio of a newspaper family. In 1916 she was the only woman to work full-time as an editorial cartoonist in America. She worked for the Columbus (Ohio) Saturday Monitor, later the Columbus Daily Monitor, 1915-1917. She is best known for her warm, friendly comic strip featuring a boy and his dog, Cap Stubbs and Tippie, which was syndicated by the George Matthew Adams Service in 1921 (The Sunday strips were distributed by King Features under the title Tippie). Other works included Sinbad, a comic strip which appeared in the old Life magazine and the London Tatler and Alec the Great, drawings which included four-line verses by her brother, Robert Dennis Dumm. She also illustrated books and sheet music, the latter in collaboration with Helen Thomas, who wrote the words and music. Edwina Dumm died in New York, New York, on April 28, 1990.
Scope and Content
Collection of original comic strips and cartoons, clippings of political cartoons, illustrated sheet music and miscellany.--Political cartoons and illustrations (1916-1917), Columbus Daily Monitor--Cap Stubbs and Tippie (daily comic strip) (1959-1961)--Tippie (Sunday strip) (1/18/48)--Alec the Great (dates unknown), with verses written by Robert Dennis Dumm--Sinbad (1923?)--sheet music: Shelter lullaby (1943); Tippie and the circus (1944); Tippie and the hurdy-gurdy (1947); Tippie's Hallowe'en serenade (1947); and the Christmas tree (1950)--photo, misc. papers, tape and transcript of oral history interview (2/15/85)
Original art works in this collection may be found by searching the library's original art database.
Statement of Arrangement
The collection is organized into ten series. Series I contains original artwork. Series II contains scrapbooks of political cartoon. Series III contains Tippie proofs and clippings. Series IV contains other materials relating to Tippie. Series V contains materials for Alec the Great and other comics. Series VI contains photographs. Series VII contains sheet music and other collaborations with Helen Thomas. Series VIII is the oral history interview with Edwina Dumm in 1987. Series IX contains personal and business correspondence. Series X contains diaries of Edwina Dumm, biographical information, memorabilia, and other assorted materials.
Related Material
Technical Requirements
The Series VII: Oral History is available on audio cassette and compact disc. The collection also contains numerous photographic slides which require a projector for viewing.
Restrictions on Access
Political cartoons limited to use of photocopies due to the fragility of the original clippings.
Other Finding Aids
A paper finding aid is available for use in the library. Inventories of original cartoons are also available.
Acquisition Information
Materials received in a series of gifts starting in 1981; Estate of Edwina Dumm, 1991; Gift of Nancy Coe, 1993, and from the Estate of Nancy Coe, donated by Jennifer Coe and Amy Bickers in 2007-2008.
Indexing Terms
The following terms have been used to index the description of this collection in the library's online public access catalog.
Subjects:
Comic books, strips, etc. -- United States; Caricatures and cartoons; Editorial cartoons; Women cartoonists -- United States; Dogs -- Caricatures and cartoons
Persons:
Dumm, Robert Dennis; Thomas, Helen, 1908-
Titles:
Columbus daily monitor; Cap Stubbs and Tippie; Tippie; Alec the Great; Sinbad; Edwina Dumm Collection; Monitor (Columbus, Ohio)
Detailed Description of The Collection
- Series I: Original Art, 1916-1982
  Series I contains original art including color pencil drawings, watercolors and sketches by Edwina Dumm. Drawings and sketches from the series Cap Stubbs and Tippie, as well as oher comic series and characters, such as Mr. Socrates, Mr. Whiskers, and Squawk are included.
  Original art works in this collection may be found by searching the library's original art database.
- Series II: Scrapbooks of political cartoons from the Columbus Daily Monitor and other clippings, 1916-1917
  Series II contains scrapbooks of clippings of editorial cartoons done by Edwina Dumm for the Columbus Daily Monitor. The scrapbooks have been disbound and the markings of "a" and "b" on pieces denote whether the clipping is from the obverse or reverse of the page. Any title followed by an asterisk (*) indicates it was dated from microfilm of the Columbus Daily Monitor. The clippings cover the years of 1916 and 1917, and cover issues such as World War I, the women's suffrage movement, and prohibition and temperance movements of the period. Photocopies of the clippings are included in the series and should be used in lieu of the clippings.
  - Scrapbook cover and "Now's the Time to Enlist", [1916-1917] (Box FED 1, Piece 1)
    Not on microfilm of Columbus Daily Monitor at the Ohio Historical Society.
  - "Our Guest", December 16, 1916 (Box FED 1, Piece 2a)
  - "Crowded Off the Stage", December 18, 1916 (Box FED 1, Piece 2b)
  - "When Dreams Come True", December 19, 1916 (Box FED 1, Piece 3a)
  - "The Magnanimous", December 20, 1916 (Box FED 1, Piece 3b)
  - "Seeking a Divorce", December 21, 1916 (Box FED 1, Piece 4a)
  - "Watchful Waiting", December 22, 1916 (Box FED 1, Piece 4b)
  - "The Joys of Yuletide", December 22, 1916 (Box FED 1, Piece 5a)
  - "Either Singed or Frozen", December 23, 1916 (Box FED 1, Piece 5b)
  - "After Christmas", December 26, 1916 (Box FED 1, Piece 6a)
  - "Slightly Improved", December 27, 1916 (Box FED 1, Piece 6b)
  - "A Beautiful Vision", December 28, 1916 (Box FED 1, Piece 7a)
  - "Forgotten in the Excitement", December 27, 1916 (Box FED 1, Piece 7b)
  - "Will It Hold?", December 28, 1916 (Box FED 1, Piece 8a)
  - "Next Stop", December 30, 1916 (Box FED 1, Piece 8b)
  - "Indoor Sports", January 1, 1917 (Box FED 1, Piece 9a)
  - "A Blamed Expensive Show", January 2, 1917 (Box FED 1, Piece 9b)
  - "A Suspicious Character", January 3, 1917 (Box FED 1, Piece 10a)
  - "Ma Dons Her War Paint", January 3, 1917 (Box FED 1, Piece 10b)
  - "Weighing His Decision", January 5, 1917 (Box FED 1, Piece 11a)
  - "Cinderella", January 6, 1917 (Box FED 1, Piece 11b)
  - "'These Are My Jewels'", January 8, 1917 (Box FED 1, Piece 12a)
  - "All Ready for the Inaugural Ball", January 8, 1917 (Box FED 1, Piece 12b)
  - "The Peace Note Started Something" *, January 9, 1917 (Box FED 1, Piece 13a)
  - "Reform Begins at Home", January 10, 1917 (Box FED 1, Piece 13b)
  - "Feedin' Time", January 11, 1917 (Box FED 1, Piece 14a)
  - "On the Long Trail", January 11, 1917 (Box FED 1, Piece 14b)
  - "For the Love of Mike, Be Reasonable", January 12, 1917 (Box FED 1, Piece 15a)
  - "Now What'll He Dish Up", January 13, 1917 (Box FED 1, Piece 15b)
  - "A Modern Sir Walter?", January 15, 1917 (Box FED 1, Piece 16a)
  - "Some Mess", January 16, 1917 (Box FED 1, Piece 16b)
  - "The Nation's Loss" *, January 17, 1917 (Box FED 1, Piece 17a)
  - "They Get Us All", January 18, 1917 (Box FED 1, Piece 17b)
  - "At It Again", January 19, 1917 (Box FED 1, Piece 18a)
  - "Which Road?", January 20, 1917 (Box FED 1, Piece 18b)
  - "Homeward Bound", January 22, 1917 (Box FED 1, Piece 19a)
  - "Which for the Job?", January 23, 1917 (Box FED 1, Piece 19b)
  - "For Humanity's Sake", January 23, 1917 (Box FED 1, Piece 20a)
  - "Mighty Hard to Get At", January 26, 1917 (Box FED 1, Piece 20b)
  - "Well! Well!", January 25, 1917 (Box FED 1, Piece 21a)
  - "When Johnny Comes Marching Home", [1916-1917] (Box FED 1, Piece 21b)
    Not on microfilm of Columbus Monitor at the Ohio Historical Society
  - "Monitor Movie News", January 27, 1917 (Box FED 1, Piece 22a)
  - "The Jumping Off Place", January 29, 1917 (Box FED 1, Piece 22b)
  - "Not Hitting It Off", January 30, 1917 (Box FED 1, Piece 23a)
  - "Mighty Aggravatin'", January 31, 1917 (Box FED 1, Piece 23b)
  - "Look Out!", February 1, 1917 (Box FED 1, Piece 24a)
  - "Up to Him Now", February 2, 1917 (Box FED 1, Piece 24b)
  - "Another 'Scrap of Paper'", February 3, 1917 (Box FED 1, Piece 25a)
  - "Better Think Twice", February 5, 1917 (Box FED 1, Piece 25b)
  - "The Answer", February 5, 1917 (Box FED 1, Piece 26a)
  - "Military Necessity" *, February 6, 1917 (Box FED 1, Piece 26b)
  - "Wearing His Own Clothes Again", February 7, 1917 (Box FED 1, Piece 27a)
  - "'Birds of a Feather'", February 8, 1917 (Box FED 1, Piece 27b)
  - "Fancied Security", February 9, 1917 (Box FED 1, Piece 28a)
  - "The Treacherous Guide", February 10, 1917 (Box FED 1, Piece 28b)
  - "The Crisis", February 12, 1917 (Box FED 1, Piece 29a)
  - "One Way of Looking at It", February 13, 1917 (Box FED 1, Piece 29b)
  - "Aw, Go On!", February 14, 1917 (Box FED 1, Piece 30a)
  - "Slipping", February 15, 1917 (Box FED 1, Piece 30b)
  - "And His Spirit Is with Us Now", February 22, 1917 (Box FED 1, Piece 31a)
  - "Desperate", February 23, 1917 (Box FED 1, Piece 31b)
  - "'Getting Riled'", February 16, 1917 (Box FED 1, Piece 32a)
  - "The Scourge", February 17, 1917 (Box FED 1, Piece 32b)
  - "An Unequal Fight", February 19, 1917 (Box FED 1, Piece 33a)
  - "What Is Gained", February 20, 1917 (Box FED 1, Piece 33b)
  - "Finis", February 20, 1917 (Box FED 1, Piece 34a)
  - "Can't Hold Him Much Longer", February 21, 1917 (Box FED 1, Piece 34b)
  - "Not on Speaking Terms", February 24, 1917 (Box FED 1, Piece 35a)
  - "Wherever He Goes, His Followers", February 26, 1917 (Box FED 1, Piece 35b)
  - "For Self-Protection", February 28, 1917 (Box FED 1, Piece 36a)
  - "The Cloud Becomes Darker", March 1, 1917 (Box FED 1, Piece 36b)
  - "Discovered in Time", March 2, 1917 (Box FED 1, Piece 37a)
  - "The End of the Trail", March 3, 1917 (Box FED 1, Piece 37b)
  - "Cheer Up! She'll Rescue Us Yet", March 5, 1917 (Box FED 1, Piece 38a)
  - "Playing into His Hands", March 6, 1917 (Box FED 1, Piece 38b)
  - "All There Is to Hang To", March 7, 1917 (Box FED 1, Piece 39a)
  - "Get That!", March 8, 1917 (Box FED 1, Piece 39b)
  - "The Record Against Him", March 9, 1917 (Box FED 1, Piece 40a)
  - "Nobody Loves Us", March 10, 1917 (Box FED 1, Piece 40b)
  - "Time for More Magnanimous Peace Offers", March 12, 1917 (Box FED 1, Piece 41a)
  - "Never Know What to Expect", March 13, 1917 (Box FED 1, Piece 41b)
  - "As Matters Stand", March 14, 1917 (Box FED 1, Piece 42a)
  - "A Fine Chance for the Old Boy", March 15, 1917 (Box FED 1, Piece 42b)
  - "Eternity", March 16, 1917 (Box FED 1, Piece 43a)
  - "Big Enough to Do It", March 17, 1917 (Box FED 1, Piece 43b)
  - "All for None--None for All!" *, March 19, 1917 (Box FED 1, Piece 44a)
  - "The Last Straw", March 20, 1917 (Box FED 1, Piece 44b)
  - "Why Not Dump the Jonah?", March 21, 1917 (Box FED 1, Piece 45a)
  - "It's About Time", March 22, 1917 (Box FED 1, Piece 45b)
  - "An Ominous Sunset", March 23, 1917 (Box FED 1, Piece 46a)
  - "Beginning to Listen", March 24, 1917 (Box FED 1, Piece 46b)
  - "Rounding Them Up" *, March 28, 1917 (Box FED 1, Piece 47a)
  - "In the Path of Kultur Homeward Bound", March 29, 1917 (Box FED 1, Piece 47b)
  - "Fashion Hints from Darkest Russia", [1917] (Box FED 1, Piece 48a)
    Not on microfilm of the Columbus Monitor at the Ohio Historical Society
  - "The Call", [1917] (Box FED 1, Piece 48b)
    Not in microfilm of the Columbus Monitor at the Ohio Historical Society
  - "Music That Was Never Popular with Royalty", March 30, 1917 (Box FED 1, Piece 49a)
  - "Why Germany Can't Win", March 31, 1917 (Box FED 1, Piece 49b)
  - "The Blind Who Won't See", April 2, 1917 (Box FED 1, Piece 50a)
  - "Ready", April 3, 1917 (Box FED 1, Piece 50b)
  - "Well--Not So That You Could Notice It", April 4, 1917 (Box FED 1, Piece 51a)
  - "Why We Must Do Our 'Bit'", April 5, 1917 (Box FED 1, Piece 51b)
  - Photocopies of political cartoons, 1917 (Box FED 1, Folder 52)
  - Scrapbook cover and "It'll Be More Than Luck", July 5, 1917 (Box FED 2, Piece 1)
  - "There's No Time to Be Lost", June 22, 1917 (Box FED 2, Piece 2a)
  - "The Cross That Reunites", June 23, 1917 (Box FED 2, Piece 2b)
  - Monitor Broadsides/A. W. Raymond, [1917] (Box FED 2, Piece 3a)
  - "His New Friend" *, June 2, 1917 (Box FED 2, Piece 3b)
  - "Nearing the End of the Road" *, May 31, 1917 (Box FED 2, Piece 4a)
  - "For the Little 'Sick-A-Bed' Folks" *, June 1, 1917 (Box FED 2, Piece 4b)
  - "Heroes Past and Present" *, May 30, 1917 (Box FED 2, Piece 5a)
  - "Buy Liberty Bonds Now and Defeat Prussianism" *, May 29, 1917 (Box FED 2, Piece 5b)
  - "Losing His Punch" *, May 28, 1917 (Box FED 2, Piece 6a)
  - Monitor Broadsides/F. H. Nichol, [1917] (Box FED 2, Piece 6b)
  - Monitor Broadsides/H. Garber, [1917] (Box FED 2, Piece 7a)
  - Monitor Broadsides, [1917] (Box FED 2, Piece 7b)
  - Monitor Broadsides, [1917] (Box FED 2, Piece 8a)
  - "Help Rescue His Victims" *, May 27, 1917 (Box FED 2, Piece 8b)
  - "Hurry Judge! Soak 'Em Hard!" *, May 26, 1917 (Box FED 2, Piece 9a)
  - "How Much Longer?" *, May 25, 1917 (Box FED 2, Piece 9b)
  - "Buy a Bond" *, May 24, 1917 (Box FED 2, Piece 10a)
  - "His Little Game Will Soon Be Over" *, May 23, 1917 (Box FED 2, Piece 10b)
  - "The Helping Hand" *, May 22, 1917 (Box FED 2, Piece 11a)
  - "Hidden Treasure Comes to Light" *, May 21, 1917 (Box FED 2, Piece 11b)
  - "There'll Be No More Time Lost" *, May 20, 1917 (Box FED 2, Piece 12a)
  - "They All Will in Time" *, May 19, 1917 (Box FED 2, Piece 12b)
  - "Tomorrow Is French Flag Day" *, May 18, 1917 (Box FED 2, Piece 13a)
  - "Can They Make It?" *, May 17, 1917 (Box FED 2, Piece 13b)
  - "Another Autocracy About to Fall" *, May 15, 1917 (Box FED 2, Piece 14a)
  - "A Lost Argument" *, May 16, 1917 (Box FED 2, Piece 14b)
  - "The Vampire" *, May 14, 1917 (Box FED 2, Piece 15a)
  - "Mother's Day, 1917" *, May 13, 1917 (Box FED 2, Piece 15b)
  - "A Fight to the Finish" *, May 12, 1917 (Box FED 2, Piece 16a)
  - "Impossible To Err in Choice" *, May 11, 1917 (Box FED 2, Piece 16b)
  - "On an Anxious Seat" *, May 10, 1917 (Box FED 2, Piece 17a)
  - "Partners" *, May 9, 1917 (Box FED 2, Piece 17b)
  - "Throwing Some Light on the Subject", [1917] (Box FED 2, Piece 18a)
  - "'Well, Not If I Know It!'", [1917] (Box FED 2, Piece 18b)
  - "Up or Down" *, May 5, 1917 (Box FED 2, Piece 19a)
  - "Undesirable Citizens" *, May 6, 1917 (Box FED 2, Piece 19b)
  - "Buy a Tag Tomorrow" *, May 4, 1917 (Box FED 2, Piece 20a)
  - "Why Not Clip His Wings?" *, May 3, 1917 (Box FED 2, Piece 20b)
  - "Unsuppressible!" *, May 2, 1917 (Box FED 2, Piece 21a)
  - "Volunteer Before It Is Too Late" *, May 1, 1917 (Box FED 2, Piece 21b)
  - "Time To Wake Up" *, April 30, 1917 (Box FED 2, Piece 22a)
  - "Rainbow's End", April 29, 1917 (Box FED 2, Piece 22b)
  - "Forerunner of the Celebration", April 28, 1917 (Box FED 2, Piece 23a)
  - "At Your Service", April 27, 1917 (Box FED 2, Piece 23b)
  - "His Two Trump Cards", April 26, 1917 (Box FED 2, Piece 24a)
  - "In Order To Equalize the War Burden", April 25, 1917 (Box FED 2, Piece 24b)
  - "Getting Too Hot To Hold Willie", April 24, 1917 (Box FED 2, Piece 25a)
  - "Too Much of a Good Thing" *, April 23, 1917 (Box FED 2, Piece 25b)
  - "As a War-Time Measure", April 22, 1917 (Box FED 2, Piece 26a)
  - "The Hindenburg 'Bee' Line Homeward", April 21, 1917 (Box FED 2, Piece 26b)
  - "The Thinker", April 20, 1917 (Box FED 2, Piece 27a)
  - "More Than Flags Needed", April 19, 1917 (Box FED 2, Piece 27b)
  - "Preparing for His 'Bit'", April 18, 1917 (Box FED 2, Piece 28a)
  - "Dr. Wilson's Spring Tonic", April 17, 1917 (Box FED 2, Piece 28b)
  - "'Nice Birdie'" *, April 16, 1917 (Box FED 2, Piece 29a)
  - "Not According to Program", April 14, 1917 (Box FED 2, Piece 29b)
  - "How Long Can Germany Hold On?", April 12, 1917 (Box FED 2, Piece 30a)
  - "Safe Until Truth Conquers", April 13, 1917 (Box FED 2, Piece 30b)
  - "Why They Sign the Suicide Pact", April 11, 1917 (Box FED 2, Piece 31a)
  - "To Victory", April 7, 1917 (Box FED 2, Piece 31b)
  - "Into the Fray", April 6, 1917 (Box FED 2, Piece 32a)
  - "'A Penny for THEIR Thoughts'", April 6, 1917 (Box FED 2, Piece 32b)
  - "Buy a Bond", [1917] (Box FED 2, Piece 33a)
  - Monitor Broadsides/A. W. Raymond, [June 1917] (Box FED 2, Piece 33b)
  - "Class of 1917", June 5, 1917 (Box FED 2, Piece 34a)
  - "Heroes of 1917", June 5, 1917 (Box FED 2, Piece 34b)
  - "Her Troublesome Ward" *, June 6, 1917 (Box FED 2, Piece 35a)
  - "Another Miscalculation" *, June 7, 1917 (Box FED 2, Piece 35b)
  - "Won't He Ever Wake Up" *, June 9, 1917 (Box FED 2, Piece 36a)
  - "It Makes an Impregnable Defense" *, June 8, 1917 (Box FED 2, Piece 36b)
  - Monitor Broadsides/J. H. Francis, [1917] (Box FED 2, Piece 37a)
  - "That Haunting Shadow" *, June 10, 1917 (Box FED 2, Piece 37b)
  - "His Fight Isn't Finished" *, June 11, 1917 (Box FED 2, Piece 38a)
  - Monitor Broadsides/J. H. Francis, [1917] (Box FED 2, Piece 38b)
  - "The Kaiser Reviews His Crack Regiment" *, June 13, 1917 (Box FED 2, Piece 39a)
  - "Sounds Pretty Reasonable" *, June 12, 1917 (Box FED 2, Piece 39b)
  - "Let 'Er Go" *, June 15, 1917 (Box FED 2, Piece 40a)
  - "He's Out" *, June 14, 1917 (Box FED 2, Piece 40b)
  - "I'll Get Him" *, June 17, 1917 (Box FED 2, Piece 41a)
  - "Still Bluffing" *, June 16, 1917 (Box FED 2, Piece 41b)
  - "Lessen Their Suffering", June 18, 1917 (Box FED 2, Piece 42a)
  - Monitor Broadsides/ E. T. Miller, [1917] (Box FED 2, Piece 42b)
  - Monitor Broadsides/E. T. Miller, [June 1917] (Box FED 2, Piece 43a)
  - "Crying for the Moon" *, June 19, 1917 (Box FED 2, Piece 43b)
  - "On the Edge" *, June 21, 1917 (Box FED 2, Piece 44a)
  - "Get in Line" *, June 20, 1917 (Box FED 2, Piece 44b)
  - Monitor Broadsides/J. W. Wheeler, [1917] (Box FED 2, Piece 45a)
  - "'He Also Serves'", June 24, 1917 (Box FED 2, Piece 45b)
  - "Not Room Enough in the World for Both" *, June 25, 1917 (Box FED 2, Piece 46a)
  - Monitor Broadsides/J. W. Wheeler, [1917] (Box FED 2, Piece 46b)
  - "Our Message to the Front", June 26, 1917 (Box FED 2, Piece 47a)
  - "The Last Stand", June 27, 1917 (Box FED 2, Piece 47b)
  - "America on the Job", June 28, 1917 (Box FED 2, Piece 48a)
  - "Wearing Out His Welcome", June 29, 1917 (Box FED 2, Piece 48b)
  - Monitor Broadsides/P. B. Clark, [1917] (Box FED 2, Piece 49a)
  - "On a Shaky Rope", July 1, 1917 (Box FED 2, Piece 49b)
  - Monitor Broadsides/P. B. Clark, [1917] (Box FED 2, Piece 50a)
  - "Russia Shows Signs of Starting Something", June 30, 1917 (Box FED 2, Piece 50b)
  - "Tomorrow the Bell Rings for the Whole World" on scrapbook cover, July 3, 1917 (Box FED 2, Piece 51)
  - "His Constant Guide", [1916-1917] (Box FED 2, Piece 52)
  - "A Pair of old 'War Horses'" and on verso Justice Chas. E. Hughes, [1916-1917] (Box FED 2, Piece 53)
  - The Meanderings of Minnie comic strip, "Minnie Tired of Bosses", [1916-1917] (Box FED 2, Piece 54)
  - Colonel Geo. A. Dodd, [1916-1917] (Box FED 2, Piece 55)
  - Side Lights on Human Nature, [1916-1917] (Box FED 2, Piece 56)
  - Photocopies of political cartoons, 1916-1917 (Box FED 2, Folder 57)
- Series III: Tippie proofs and clippings, 1920-1980
  Series III contains collections of proof sheets of the Tippie comic series. Proofs are preliminary versions of publications meant for review for examination or correction. The series also contains newspaper clippings of the strip, photographic slides of the strip, and photographs of proofs.
  - "Cap" Stubbs daily proofs, 1922 (Box FED 2, Folder 65)
  - Tippie daily proofs, 1920-1931 (Box FED 3, Folder 1-12)
    Proofs are numbered and range from #131082 to #134592.
  - Tippie daily proofs, 1932-1947 (Box FED 4, Folder 1-16)
    Each folder contains a one year run of proofs. Some of the proofs are numbers including a range from #134593 to #137773. The runs of years 1942 (FED Box 4, Folder 11) and 1943 (FED Box 4, Folder 12) are incomplete.
  - Tippie daily proofs, 1948-1966 (Box FED 5, Folder 1)
    Each folder contains a one year run of proofs. The runs of years 1948 (FED Box 5, Folder 1) and 1943 (FED Box 5, Folder 3) are incomplete.
  - Tippie loose pieces, [1950s-1960s] (Box FED 6, Folder 4)
  - Sinbad logo and Tippie Sunday (8-3-1941) individual panel copies, 1980 (Box FED 6, Folder 6)
  - Tippie newspaper clippings, 1921 (Box FED 6, Folder 15)
  - Bound Tippie daily proofs, 1939 (Box FED 7, Folder 2)
  - Scrapbooks of Tippie daily proofs, 1948-1954 (Box FED 7, Folder 3-7)
  - Box of Tippie photographic slides, undated (Box FED 7, Folder 8-9)
  - Box of photographic slides of Tippie Sunday strips, undated (Box FED 7, Folder 10)
  - Scrapbook of Tippie daily proofs, 1955-1956 (Box FED 8, Folder 1)
  - Scrapbook of Tippie Sunday newspaper clippings, 1946-1949 (Box FED 8, Folder 2-3)
  - Tippie Sunday proofs book, 1937-1950 (Box FED 9, Folder 1-4)
  - Tippie daily proofs book, 1965-1966 (Box FED 9, Folder 5)
  - Newspaper clipping of "Cap" Stubbs & Tippie, December 2, 1922 (Box FED 10, Folder 3)
  - Photographs of Tippie Sunday proofs, 1939-1948 (Box FED 10, Folder 12)
  - Zinc plate of Tippie daily, August 5th, [1920s-1960s] (Box FED 10, Piece 27)
- Series IV: Tippie related materials, 1920-1982
  Series IV contains materials related to the Tippie character which are not proofs or clippings. The series contains script ideas for the cartoon, merchandise, and materials related to a Tippie film project.
  - Tippie happy birthday greeting, 1978 (Box FED 6, Folder 3)
  - Tippie advertisement layout, undated (Box FED 6, Folder 13)
  - Tippie film credits layout and bills, 1978-1982 (Box FED 6, Folder 27)
  - Tippie and Cap Stubbs storyline books, 1943-1956 (Box FED 6, Folder 41-44)
  - Tippie statue, undated (Box FED 6, Piece 49)
  - Tippie dinner plates, undated (Box FED 6, Piece 50-51)
    Two hand-inked and watercolored dinner plates with the figure of Tippie. One is labeled with the text, "Tippie's Dinner Song."
  - Tippie contacts, 1979-1982 (Box FED 10, Folder 7)
  - Ideals Publishing material for Tippie and His Friends, 1975-1981 (Box FED 10, Folder 10)
  - Foldout advertisements for Tippie, undated (Box FED 10, Folder 11)
  - Newspaper clippings about Edwina and Tippie, [1930s-1980s] (Box FED 10, Folder 13)
  - Unique Tippie material (unpublished round songbook) and Alec the Great calendar, [1940s]-1975 (Box FED 10, Folder 18)
  - Miscellaneous Tippie pieces, undated (Box FED 10, Folder 23)
  - Mounted Tippie scene layouts with captions, undated (Box FED 10, Folder 24)
  - Tippie moving picture film leader, [1970s-1980s] (Box FED 10, Piece 28)
  - Box of photographic slides of Tippie drawings, undated (Box FED 10, Folder 29)
  - Box of Tippie photographic slides, [1979] (Box FED 10, Folder 30)
  - Notebooks of Tippie script ideas, 1942-1963 (Box FED 10, Folder 32-43, Box FED 11, Folder 1-4)
    Some of the journals contain correspondence from Peter Wells.
- Series V: Alec the Great and other comics, 1949-1967